http://www.peace.edu/privacy-policy/

Skip to content Skip to menu Home Back Back to Main MenuAboutAboutWPU at a GlanceMission, Vision and ValuesLeadershipLeadershipSenior Leadership TeamPresident’s BiographyStrategic PlanBoard of TrusteesState of The UniversityHistory & TraditionDirectoryLocations & DirectionsConferences & Rental SpaceConferences & Rental SpaceFacility RentalsResidential ConferencesWeddingsCatering OptionsContact UsStudent Consumer InformationAdmissionsAdmissionsFirst-YearAdults & ProfessionalTransferMilitary & VeteransInternational StudentsAdmissions FAQ’sPlan a VisitMeet the Admissions TeamHigh School CounselorsRequest InformationApplyAccepted StudentsAccepted StudentsFirst Year OrientationPay My DepositParents & FamiliesCosts, Scholarships & Financial AidCosts, Scholarships & Financial AidTuition & FeesTuition & FeesPayment Options and Due DatesTuition Insurance PlanNet Price CalculatorScholarships and AwardsCommunity Service and Leadership ScholarshipsWilliam Peace Pathways – Scholarship for WTCC TransfersHow to Apply for Financial AidMeet the Financial Aid TeamAcademicsAcademicsPrograms of StudyAdult & Professional StudiesAdult & Professional StudiesAbout School of Professional StudiesProfessional Studies ProgramsLearning OpportunitiesFinancial Aid for the AdultApplyMeet the SPS TeamSPS Referral ProgramMeet Our FacultyExperiential + Immersive LearningExperiential + Immersive LearningInternshipsStudy AbroadStudent Research OpportunitiesShowcaseCenter for Student SuccessCenter for Student SuccessAcademic and Tutoring CenterFirst Year ExperienceHonors ProgramDisability ServicesWPU ConnectCareer ServicesAcademic ResourcesAcademic ResourcesAcademic CalendarAcademic CatalogCourse & Final Exam SchedulesWilliam Peace University Summer Courses 2021LibraryCooperating Raleigh Colleges (CRC)Core CurriculumOffice of the RegistrarStudent LifeStudent LifeHousing & DiningHousing & DiningResidential LifeDiningSafety & SecurityPacer AthleticsClubs, Activities & RecreationClubs, Activities & RecreationPacer AthleticsIntramuralsCommunity ServiceShowcaseHealth & WellnessStudent Support ServicesStudent Support ServicesComputer Labs & ITDisability ServicesPacerCardSafety & SecurityTitle IXTitle IXSexual Assault Prevention Training for StudentsTransportationWilliam Peace University BookstoreDiversity & InclusionFirst Year OrientationFirst Year OrientationFamily & Guest OrientationMeet the Student Life StaffCommencement 2020 + 2021Commencement 2020 + 2021Commencement General FAQsCommencement Day FAQsBaccalaureate Ceremony FAQsCareer Design CenterCareer Design CenterJob SearchPrepare for Graduate SchoolCareer Design for StudentsCareer Design for AlumniEmployer RelationsOur RaleighAlumni & GivingAlumni & GivingGet InvolvedGiveGiveFounder’s Day of Giving 2020Giving PrioritiesGiving SocietiesPeace Cares FundStay EngagedAlumni BenefitsAlumni BoardOffice of AdvancementOffice of AdvancementMeet the Advancement TeamPacer AthleticsParents & FamiliesDirectoryCareers at WPUQuick LinksMyPacerNetStudent MailMoodleLibrary LoginBookstoreShop WPU GearGive to PeaceWilliam Peace TheatreRent Our Facilities Menu Search Search For:
Menu Search William Peace University
Visit PeaceVirtual TourRequest InfoApply Now
HomePrivacy PolicyOnline Privacy PolicyWilliam Peace UniversityOffice of Information Technology * 11/11/2019This policy discloses the privacy practices for most websites within the Peace.edu domain. We understand the privacy concerns of our website visitors. William Peace University collects information from visitors when they access peace.edu to provide visitors with a better online experience with the university.What information do we collect?The university (including through third-party providers) may collect some identifiable information about how visitors access and use websites affiliated with the peace.edu domain. This information includes IP address, browser, geolocation, device type and more. Cookies may be used to facilitate the navigation of this site, but these cookies do not contain information that alone can identify individuals.The generic information collected by William Peace is based on IP address, which is the location of a computer or network. For admission and recruiting purposes, some IP addresses and cookies may be collected and stored; when used in conjunction with a third-party system, individuals’ information may be identified. This information will not be used beyond admissions offices, unless required to do so by law. In most other instances, William Peace will not associate an IP address and/or web usage data with any other university information that could specifically identify a visitor, unless required to do so by law.Some webpages within peace.edu may also collect personal data through forms, surveys, event registration, newsletter subscriptions, etc. This information helps William Peace communicate with individuals who have expressed interest in receiving information from the university, such as registering for an event, submitting an application, etc.If you are an applicant for admission or parent or family member of an applicant, certain required and optional information is collected from you when you provide this information via the online application.  We use this information only for application review and scholarship purposes. If you make a deposit for your application or make tuition payments, you will be directed to our third-party payment processors.  We do not store payment information.  The privacy policies of those processors will apply to any information you submit.If you are a prospective student and complete a “Contact Us” form, such as to request information from us or to schedule a campus tour, we may collect certain required and optional information from you, including your name, email address, birth date, intended enrollment date, your areas of academic interest, your phone number (including mobile number), your address, gender, race/ethnicity, your interest in athletics, request for accommodations for a tour, your parents’ names and email addresses, and whether you are related to a University graduate.If you share news with us about your accomplishments, we may collect certain information you provide us about your internship, career, graduate school plans, etc.  We may collect your name, University email address, major, minor, class year, hometown, move-in day experience, and other career information you share with us, as well as pictures you upload.What do we use your information for?With non-personally identifiable information such as IP addresses, William Peace is able to:Personalize and enhance visitors’ experiences,Improve the website and/orHelp diagnose problems with the university’s server.If a visitor fills out a form, completes a survey or subscribes to a newsletter using personal information, such as an email address, the email address provided may be used to send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.How do we protect your information?William Peace implements a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of visitors’ personal information, including the use of a secure server for private data, such as credit cards, Social Security numbers, etc. After a transaction is complete, credit card and private information is not stored on our servers.Remember: No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100 percent secure.Do we use cookies?Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to a visitor’s computer’s hard drive through his/her web browser that enables William Peace to recognize the browser, capture and remember certain information, such as user preferences, and collect aggregate data about site traffic.Visitors may refuse the use of cookies by adjusting browser settings—though disabling cookies may prevent visitors from using the full functionality of some WPU websites.Cookies may be set by an organization other than William Peace, such as YouTube, Twitter, Facebook, Google Plus or other social media services for which the university has implemented “plug-ins.” Information on their cookie policies can be found on these sites directly.Do we disclose any information to outside parties?William Peace does not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer personally identifiable information gathered from website traffic to outside parties. WPU may share user information with third-party partners as necessary to provide and improve web services or other communications to users. Third parties who receive user information for this purpose are prohibited from using or sharing the data for any purpose other than providing services to users.Information also may be provided to third parties in circumstances in which doing so is necessary or appropriate to: satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request; detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; or protect the rights, property or safety of campus, users or others. Non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising or other uses.Third-party linksWebsites on peace.edu often provide links to third-party websites as a convenience to users. William Peace University does not control third-party websites and is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of any linked-to, third-party websites or any hyperlink in a linked-to website. Google AnalyticsMany sections of peace.edu use Google Analytics to help understand how visitors use the website. Through Google Analytics, the university can obtain visitors’ cookie data, such as the source, medium and IP address. This information is transmitted to and stored by Google on its servers. Google will use this information to evaluate visitors’ website use, compile reports on website activity, and provide other services relating to Internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate a visitor’s IP address with any other data held by Google. By using peace.edu, visitors consent to Google’s data collection and processing.Find more information on Google Analytics terms of use and privacy practices.Advertising and RemarketingSome parts of peace.edu may use the Google AdWords or other third-party retargeting/remarketing services to advertise to previous visitors to the site through third-party websites. Such third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on someone’s past visits to this website. Any data collected will be used in accordance with William Peace, Google and other third-party privacy policies.Opt-outYou may opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads by visiting the Ads Preferences Manager. To opt out of other advertising and retargeting, email webteam@peace.edu. You also can manage all of your browser’s advertising preferences and, if desired, opt-out on the Network Advertising Initiative website.Website Privacy Statement OnlyThis website privacy statement applies only to information collected through peace.edu and not to information collected offline.Contact UsIf there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, please contact the University by calling (919) 508-2000.
